11 artists remain but only one of you
will earn $100,000 a feature in Inked
Magazine and the title of ink master
last week you had to battle on your own
but sometimes your best strategy is to
follow a leader that's been here before
who's it gonna be this week both of your
coaches made it all the way to the
finale and they also happen to
specialize in the same style
jime litwalk yes nice and Kelly Dodie
yes
welcome back coaches hi I've never
coached before so I'm coming into this
with absolutely no plan which I think
could be an advantage I know what it
feels like to be under this kind of
pressure I feel like I can pass along to
knowledge to these artists that could
truly help them out Jimmy will coach the
women's team and Kelly will coach the
men's team dicks first that's how I roll
coaches your success in this competition
is tied directly to that of your team
save all your artists from elimination
and you will earn a spot in the clash of
the coaches faceoff for $25,000 this
week we are testing color theory color
theory
is the ability to pick and choose
different colors that are gonna play off
each other if you do not know color
theory your art and your tattoos will
fall flat for this flash challenge
you'll be working with basic tattoo
supplies but
you won't be tattooing instead you must
think outside the box to create a work
of art using only tattoo ink and ink
caps that's why you here think outside
the box by mixing and blending nothing
but primary colors you must fill over
11,000 ink caps to create a single
colorful masterpiece complicated part is
laying out your design and how to turn
whatever you want to make into this
pixelated image because it needs to be a
big clear open legible design you guys
are working with two coaches that
completely get it so I would really
listen and see the way that they push
color off of each other be creative as
always if you don't have a strong
understanding of color theory your
design will be a disaster
thank you win this challenge and your
team will have the power to assign all
the human canvases in the Elimination
tattoo you'll have six hours and your
time starts
okay sketchbooks so can everyone kind of
unite and please vote that she should
figure out what the hell we're doing
yeah today I'd like to see something
first and foremost that I know what I'm
looking at what are you thinking what it
would like doing almost like a monarch
butterflies yeah
we're not that mido we're only giving
them the primary colors so everything
they do they have to mix maybe a lantern
with moms heading towards it if they
never learned real color theory then
they're gonna struggle so that way you
get a light source so that you have
dichotomy between muted colors up
against bright colors color theory is
literally my favorite part of the
artistic process so we need a big a
scale on a black if we do the background
black that's not color theory what
happens with colors is warm colors move
forward and cool colors recede I tend to
use a limited color palette and when you
start using muted colors that makes your
vivid colors look that much more
impactful I feel like our small moth
should be the whole size of this paper
they're doing know that I'm are you
serious the other drew they literally do
everything we do
I think apples apples and or does it
look better Yeah right all right so are
you gonna help me lay this shit out me
yeah if you guys drew at all didn't you
you should try it that's not in there
I'm really trying to take a more like
free-spirited artistic approach and just
kind of draw this thing on
you honestly drew it too tall so really
you only about they only get this lunch
every weird dude you have never picked
up a pencil one time during the flash
challenge you have never drawn anything
I feel like all this needs to do is I
feel like this look completely weird
right now if they were artists I would
think that they would know exactly what
the I'm doing this should be to be
perfect to see what it is and just start
this whole shit over I just thought it
was gonna be best to just draw it on the
canvas for working you know I'm saying
we can refine it once we have like the
bare bones of it all set up three hours
guys halfway there
three more hours left
she's like a wizard whatever let her
work I have a color artist I love to
tattoo colors so when I can get in there
and cut different colors and make this
unique color that's not in a bottle I
think this is my day what is this it's
the one that you said that I conjured I
conjured upon you did it again yeah
wizard mixer over here this is fun
[Music]
this is your final hour everybody final
hours it was better before such a good
green is like the color of my tears
their stuff looks tonal look at it it's
all one color except for the orange
right no the brown and the purple
background do not color theory there
anyway we can make this thing not look
like yet in the next 30 minutes five
four three two one that's it time is up
good teamwork
[Applause]
I don't think that orange morph is gonna
turn out like that it looks sweet
you killed that jewel awesome alright it
is now time to critique your work let's
start with the men's team you guys
definitely show off your color theory in
the back loss in contrast to the light
you do a lot of great work in blending
and I love to play between orange and
gray all the tones to yellow and to
black from both of those makes for a
very interesting cool to warm the ratio
ain't worried about this shit I think we
got so much to say about ours alright
women's team you're up I personally love
all the different tones of the green and
the blues and aquas for the record
everything up there is mixed Janel she
was spot-on it was one of those scenes
those Reds are mixed everything is mixed
nice the gradation that you have in the
wings from dark to light towards the
center of jewel is really nice and
there's a great color theory between the
red and the green which contrasts with
your blue and then offsetting with your
golden frame that shows strong color
theory
[Music]